tesa.com 2016-04-11

# Privacy Policy - Privacy - tesa SE

## Data Privacy Statement

This Privacy Statement is intended to inform you about the collection, processing and utilization (hereinafter "use") of personal data. See section 8 regarding how you can refuse use of your personal data in accordance with applicable data privacy provisions.

## 1\. Name and address of responsible entity:

tesa SE  
Online Management  
Hugo-Kirchberg-Strasse 1  
22848 Norderstedt  
Germany

## 2\. Managing director:

Dr. Robert Gereke (Chief Executive Officer), Jan Christoph Teetz (Chief Financial Officer), Oliver Höfs (Member of the Executive Board, Trade Markets)

## 3\. Subject of data privacy 

The subject of data privacy is personal data. Under the Federal Data Protection Act, personal data are individual disclosures regarding the private or material circumstances of an identified or identifiable natural person. This includes, for example, name, mailing address, e-mail address and phone number and potentially also usage data such as your IP address.

## 4\. Purpose of data collection, processing or utilization: 

tesa SE collects, processes and utilizes (hereinafter "uses") personal data provided by you as necessary for the preparation, conclusion, execution or termination of a transaction or transaction-like relationship with you and/or for the use of services provided by us. Such a relationship arises, for example, when you contact us to obtain information regarding us or our products, or when you use the extranet login as a customer. In such cases tesa uses your personal data in order to process your respective inquiry.

## 5\. Use of personal data for advertising and market research purposes:

If you consent to the use of your personal data for advertising and market research purposes, tesa will use your data for the purposes to which you have granted consent (e.g. newsletter) until you revoke such consent – see point 8. This means that tesa may contact you via the channels specified in the consent declaration (e-mail, telephone, regular mail etc.) and send you information and advertising about our products and services based on analysis of your individual purchasing and click behavior on our websites. tesa additionally uses your data to analyze use of its website for enhancement purposes. 

Consent to use of your personal data for advertising and market research purposes must be expressly given, for example by checking a corresponding box. If you wish for your personal data to no longer be used for advertising and/or market research purposes, you may revoke consent at any time. The procedure for doing so is outlined here [link to point 8 below (revocation)]."

## 6\. Recipients or groups of recipients to whom the data may be disclosed:

It may be necessary in processing your inquiries to disclose your personal data to affiliated companies within the tesa group or to external service providers acting exclusively on tesa’s behalf. An example of such a service provider bound by tesa’s instructions is a newsletter dispatch provider. tesa ensures that external service providers use your personal data exclusively in compliance with its instructions, this Privacy Statement and legal requirements governing contract data processing. 

tesa upholds confidentially regarding your personal data at all times, and does not disclose it to third parties who are not acting on tesa’s behalf unless you have either consented to such disclosure in writing or electronically, or tesa is legally entitled or required by law to do so.

## 7\. Use of cookies

"Cookies" are used on our websites. Cookies are small text files stored by your browser on the hard drive of your computer. **

a. Cookies for improving the functionality of our websites

**  
One reason tesa employs cookies is to better understand how its websites are used in order to enhance their attractiveness, content and functionality. Cookies help tesa, for example, to determine what pages of its website are visited and what content interests users. For these purposes tesa uses flash cookies and load time optimization cookies. These so-called "first-party cookies" record, in particular, the number of times a page is accessed, the number of website pages viewed, the amount of time spent on tesa websites, the sequence of pages visited, the search terms that led you to tesa’s site, the country, region and possibly the city from where the site is being accessed, the operating system and internet browser used, your language setting and how often tesa websites are accessed by mobile devices. tesa also records mouse movements, clicks and scrolling to find out which areas of its website are of particular interest to visitors. The IP address of your computer, which is transmitted for technical reasons, is automatically rendered anonymous so that your identity cannot be determined.  
As a registered user you have the option of signing in to tesa’s website using your registration data, i.e. "logging in". In such cases tesa also uses cookies to identify you as a registered customer upon a repeat visit to its website within a 28-day period and to allow you to remain logged in.  
During your first visit to tesa’s website, a popup will appear at the upper edge of the screen asking you to confirm whether you agree to the utilization of cookies. The button provided can be used to agree. If you change your mind later on, simply delete all of the cookies stored by your browser.   
**  
b. Cookies for usage-based online advertising**  
tesa reserves the right to use data obtained by analyzing the usage behavior of visitors to its websites via cookies in order to display specific advertising for certain tesa products on tesa’s websites. tesa believes that you benefit from this as a user because tesa displays advertising banners or content based on your surfing behavior so as to match your interests, reducing random advertising and displaying of content likely of less interest to you.  
 **  
c. How to prevent "cookies" from being stored on your hard drive and delete these**  
You can configure your internet browser to prevent cookies from being stored on your hard drive or to be asked every time whether you agree to the placement of cookies. You may also delete placed cookies at any time. Consult your browser's Help to read about how all this works in detail. An explanation with screenshots is available for the web browsers Firefox, Microsoft Internet Explorer and Google Chrome via this link: [http://www.aboutcookies.org/Default.aspx?page=2.](http://www.aboutcookies.org/Default.aspx?page=2) If you do not accept the storing of cookies, the functionality of our offerings may be impaired. 

## Third-party cookies used by tesa

 **(1) Google Analytics**  
This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA ("Google"). Google Analytics uses a specific form of "cookies", which are text files stored on your computer allowing analysis of your website usage. The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website is usually sent to a Google server in the US where it is stored. tesa would like to point out that the code "gat._anonymizeIp();" has been added to Google Analytics on this website to ensure anonymous recording of IP addresses, known as "IP masking"). Google IP anonymization on this website truncates your IP address within the EU and EEC territory. Only in exceptional cases will the full IP address be sent to a Google server in the US and truncated there.   
On our behalf, Google will use this information to analyze your use of the website, compile reports on website activity and provide other website and internet usage-related services for the website operator. The IP address transmitted by your browser as part of Google Analytics is not merged with other Google data. You may refuse the storing of cookies by changing your browser settings accordingly, see item 7. c. above; You can also prevent recorded data generated by the cookie concerning your use of the website (including your IP address) from being sent to Google and prevent the processing of this data by Google by downloading and installing the browser plugin available via the link http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de. Additional information on the Terms of Use and Data Privacy Policy may be found athttp://www.google.com/analytics/terms/de.html bzw. unter  http://www.google.com/intl/de/analytics/privacyoverview.html. 

**(2) Google Adwords**  
This website uses Google AdWords, a Google analytical service, and also conversion tracking as part of Google AdWords. Google AdWords places a conversion tracking cookie on your computer's hard drive (called a "conversion cookie") whenever you click on an ad delivered by Google. These cookies become ineffective after 30 days and are not used for personal identification. If you visit specific pages of our website, Google and tesa can track whether were forwarded to that page by clicking on an ad.

Data obtained through use of conversion cookies are used for statistical reporting for AdWords customers who employ conversion tracking. These statistics tell us the total number of users who clicked on the ad delivered by Google and opened a webpage having a conversion tracking tag. We do no however receive any information allowing personal identification of users. We are unable to cross-reference the data obtained to any specific user.

In addition to conversion tracking tesa also utilizes the functionalities

* Remarketing  
* Audiences with common interests  
* User-defined audiences with common interests  
* Purchase-willing audiences  
* Similar audiences * demographic and geographic targeting.

The Google Remarketing functionality allows tesa to reach users who have previously visited tesa’s website by showing advertising to audiences already interested in our products or services. AdWords also determines what common interests there are and shared characteristics among users of tesa’s website based on user behavior on websites in the Google Display Network in the last 30 days and contextual search engine data. Based on this information, AdWords then finds new prospective customers to market to whose interests and characteristics are similar to those of users of our website. Target-audience-specific remarketing occurs through use of cookies in combination, such as Google Analytics cookies and Google DoubleClick cookies.

Additional information regarding terms of use and privacy policy in connection with Google AdWords is available via this link: <http://www.google.de/policies/technologies/ads/>.

 **(3) Google Double Click**  
tesa uses the Google DoubleClick function on our websites to analyze website use and enable Google and other advertisers cooperating with DoubleClick to display user-relevant advertising to you. For this purpose, a cookie is placed on your computer's hard drive. This cookie assigns an identification number to your browser as a pseudonym and gathers information about advertising appearing in your browser and opening of such advertising. The data gathered by the cookie about your website use is generally sent to a Google server in the United States where it is stored. Interest-relevant categories are assigned to your browser based on the information gathered. These categories are employed in delivering interest-based advertising.   
In addition to changing your browser settings, you can also use a browser plug-in to permanently disable the DoubleClick cookie. With the plug-in, your opt-out settings remain in place for that browser even if you delete all cookies. The browser plug-in for permanent deactivation can be found here: <https://www.google.com/settings/ads/plugin?hl=de>

By using our website you consent to placement of the DoubleClick cookie, thereby consenting to the collection, storage and use of the usage data fort he stated purpose in the manner outlined above. You also consent to your data being stored in cookies after the end of the browser session and being further referenced, for example during your next website visit. This consent may be revoked at any time with non-retroactive effect by deleting the DoubleClick cookie and revoking permanent deactivation . 

**The table below lists the third-party cookies used by tesa:**

Name| Description| Validity| Cookie type  
---|---|---|---  
PHPSESSION| Saves the userâ€™s session in order to obtain information on the server side between individual requests| Session| Type 1  
eu-cookie | Records that the user has viewed the EUCookie-advisory | 10 years | Typee 2   
search-history | This cookie stores website search queries in order to display the last search terms when the search engine is opened again.| 30 days | Type 2   
press-cart-*| In the Media area: saves the IDs of media marked for download by the user. | Session| Type 1  
Google Analytics| | |   
_ga | Google Analytics is the Google analysis tool that und App-makes user interaction with the resources offered transparent for website and app owners. Google Analytics may utilize certain cookies to collect data and forward website usage statistics, without however collecting information that would make individual users personally identifiable by Google. The most important Google Analytics cookie is called "__ga". | 2 years| Type 3,4  
_utma  
_utmb  
_utmc  
_utmz| These cookies are for collecting information about how visitors use tesaâ€™s local websites. tesa uses this information to generate reports and improve the local websites. The cookies collect information anonymously about such data as number of site visitors, from what site visitors came to the local site and what pages they have visited.| 2 years  
30 min.  
End of visit  
2 years| Type 3,4  
_gat_* | Google Analytics* | 10 minutes | Type 3,4  
_gali | Google Analytics* | -| Type 3,4  
_dc_gtm_* | Google Tag Manager| 10 Minutes | Type 3,4  
YouTube| | |   
PREF  
VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE  
YSC  
ACTIVITY  
_utma  
_utmz  
dkv| Occasionally tesa integrates YouTube-videos. The use of cookies by YouTube is governed by Google data privacy policies. For further information consult [Cookie-Youtubeâ€™s policies](http://www.google.es/intl/de/policies/technologies/Types/) .| 2 Years  
8 Months  
Session  
Session  
2 years  
6 Monate  
60 days| Type 3,4  
| | |   
Cookie Types| | |   
Type 1| Absolutely necessary cookies| These cookies are absolutely necessary for websites to function properly. Without these cookies, such services as the vehicle configurator cannot be provided. |   
Type 2| FunctionalCookies | These cookies make it possible to enhance the convenience and performance of websites and provide various functionalities. For example, language settings can be stored in functional cookies. |   
Type 3| PerformanceCookies| These cookies collect information about how you use websites. Performance cookies help tesa, for example, to identify the most popular elements of its internet offerings. This enables tesa to tailor its websites more closely to your needs, thus improving tesaâ€™s offerings for you. These cookies do not collect person-specific data. |   
Type 4| Third-party cookies| These cookies are set by third parties, such as social networks. They are primarily utilized to integrate social media content such as social plug-ins into our website. For information about how tesa uses social plugins, see the "Social Plugins" section of the Privacy Statement. |   

*) Google Analytics writes a number of cookies for analyzing user behavior. These do not however gather user-specific data. These do not however gather user-specific data. 

## 8\. Social plugins 

Our websites make use of "social plugins", i.e. plugins for social networks, including particularly the Facebook "Share" button. The facebook.com website is operated by Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA. Responsible for the German website facebook.de is Facebook Ireland Limited, Hanover Reach, 5-7 Hanover Quay, Dublin 2, Ireland. The plug-ins usually feature the Facebook logo. Besides Facebook, tesa uses plug-ins by Google+ (provider: Google Inc., Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA), Twitter (provider: Twitter, Inc., 1355 Market St, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103) and Pinterest (provider: Pinterest Inc., 808 Brannan Street San Francisco, CA 94103, USA).  
For data privacy reasons tesa has deliberately opted against utilizing direct social network plug-ins on our websites. Instead, tesa employs an alternative technical solution that allows you to decide whether to transmit data to the social network operators and when. Thus when you visit our sites, data are never automatically transmitted to social networks such as Facebook, Google, Twitter or Pinterest. Only when you actively click on the respective button yourself will your web browser connect to the servers of the respective social network, i.e. clicking on elements then clicking on the social network's icon indicates your consent to your browser connecting to the servers of the respective social network and sending usage data to that social network operator.  
tesa has no influence over the nature or scope of data that social networks may then gather. For information regarding the purpose and scope of data collection, further processing and use of data by social networks and regarding your data privacy rights and relevant configuration settings, see the social networks' respective data privacy advisories. For Facebook see <http://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/> und <http://www.facebook.com/help/?faq=186325668085084>. 

More information on data usage by Google+ and Twitter can be found at <http://www.google.de/intl/de/policies/privacy/> bzw. <http://twitter.com/privacy>, and for Pinterest at <http://about.pinterest.com/privacy/>.

## 9\. Contact, information, revocation, restriction, deletion

Under the German Federal Data Protection Act you have the right to obtain information free of charge regarding what personal data of yours is stored, and to the correction, restriction and/or deletion of such stored data. 

Upon request tesa will notify you whether and what personal data about you tesa has stored. Upon your request tesa will correct or update without delay any incorrect or outdated information about you which tesa has stored. Should you no longer consent to the use of your personal data, you may at any time revoke consent to such use and/or demand partial or full restriction or deletion thereof.

For questions regarding the collection, processing or use of your personal data, to request information, correction, restriction or deletion of the data and to revoke previously granted consent, please contact us as follows:

tesa SE  
Online Management  
Hugo-Kirchberg-Strasse 1  
22848 Norderstedt  
Germany

or use our Contact form.
